

sriranjani2410@gmail.com +91-9620270987 Vellore, Tamil Nadu DOB:24/10/1995

# **Summary**

Dedicated Sales and business development professional with a never-give-up attitude with over 4 years of experience in B2B and B2C sales, Key accounts management, team management, recruiting, and operations. Ability to work in a fast-paced, dynamic environment and adapt to new situations and challenges. Willingness to take on additional responsibilities to achieve team goals.

# **Experience**

# e-con Systems India Pvt. Ltd | Chennai, Tamil Nadu Sr. Business Development Executive | 05/2022 - Present

- Responsible for new client onboarding, integration, and developing existing client relationships.
- Identified new business opportunities in the US market through cold calling, personalized emails, networking with LI, marketing, and prospective database leads. Made an average of 80-100 outbound calls per day.
- Built and maintained strong relationships with C-level executives, decision-makers, and members of the community to promote long-term business growth and identify untapped opportunities in their organization.
- Developed an advanced understanding of products and services to react to customer objections, competitive questions, and other FAQs.
- Won new business by using presentations to show prospects the full value of the company's capabilities.
- Coordinated with internal & cross-functional teams to ensure the timely delivery of products.
- Point of contact for key customer accounts and long-term relationships with clients.
- Fostered lasting relationships with customers through effective communication and quick response, resulting in long-term loyalty and an expanded client base.

# Think & Learn Pvt. Ltd (Byju's Classes) | Chennai, Tamil Nadu Business Development Manager | 01/2017 - 06/2019

- Managed a team of 30 BDAs and 3 Managers directly as a Team Manager and guided them with the sales pitch
  and reference material as needed to close certain deals and trained more than 300+ BDAs with cold calling and
  direct sales closing pitch.
- Achieved sales targets through effective planning, setting sales goals, analyzing performance and data, and projecting future performance.
- Created call audit and feedback reports by tracking weekly sales. Monitored and tracked sales team performance to enable them to succeed.
- Assisted my team with opening and closing procedures and suggested changes to improve the efficiency of daily activities.
- Recruited candidates with a heavy emphasis on sales & marketing as well as creatively sourced sales talent.,
   within a rapidly growing educational institution.
- Planned marketing initiatives and leveraged referral networks to promote business development.
- Established and maintained highly effective relationships with clients to drive growth.

# Think & Learn Pvt. Ltd (Byju's Classes) | Chennai, Tamil Nadu Business Development Manager | 02/2016 - 12/2016

- Improved bottom-line profitability by growing customer base and capitalizing on upselling & cross-selling opportunities.
- Made an average of 100 outbound calls per day. Prospected 8-10 potential customers per week through effective calling and maintained a solid 60% conversion rate.
- Negotiated contracts and closed sales with new and existing clients through effective and consistent follow-ups.
- Reviewed client concerns and recommended appropriate changes to supervisors.
- Maintained an extensive knowledge of company products and services to provide top-notch expertise to customers.
- Assisted my other team members with sales closing& pitch training.
- Researched, analyzed, and projected market data for potential markets.
- Retained highly escalated customers whose complaints are posted on social media platforms like Twitter, Facebook, etc.,

#### **Education**

2012 - 2016 B.E: Electronics And Communication Engineering | Scored 7.8 CGPA.

Gnanamani College of Engineering | Salem, India.

2011- 2012 HSC - May 2010 - Apr 2 | Scored 90.2%.

Bharathi Hr. Sec School | Namakkal, India.

SSLC - Apr 2009 - Apr 2010 | Scored 90.6%

St. Joseph Girls Hr. Sec School | Salem, Tamil Nadu.

#### **Skills**

- Retention & New Business Development.
- Leadership & Team Handling.
- Stakeholder & Vendor Management.
- MS Office, Excel & PowerPoint.

# **Accomplishments**

- Promoted 4 times in 3 consecutive years with a salary hike of 40% for my performance.
- Ranked no.1 in PAN India for consecutive 3 months out of 100 managers.
- Always ranked in the top 15 of 100 managers.
- Created and promoted 7 members as Managers out of 30 members.
- Was the company's first and only manager to achieve 50K DRPS, up from 25K previously.

## Awards & Recognition

- Awarded as sales Mavericks and an article about my journey is published in Byju's portal.
- In order of honor, Best Managers Performance Co. took me to Russia & Dubai on a Paid Trip.

## Languages Known

English, Tamil & Malayalam.